You're about to watch a coaching call
that I'm about to do with someone called
Vicky. I've never spoken to her before.
However,
we overcome some challenges of her getting
into the fitness industry in
her 50s,
and she's got a very interesting story.
And I want you to make sure you commit to
at least the first 10 minutes.
I really want Vicky to win.
I hope I've given out all the information
that she
needs to go from zero to one,
to book her diary,
to get some online clients, and
to really protect her future. This was,
yeah,
almost an emotional one for me as well,
and I really think
if you give her the time of day,
not only is there lots of lessons you can
learn
yourself,
I think it'll make you want to feel like
me in championing her to doing
very well. So,
enjoy this call. It's about 90 minutes,
and I'm sure that everyone can
benefit from this. So enjoy.
We will begin with, how can I help you?
[chuckles]
Okay. Well,
so I'm very new to this. Like brand
new.
I'm even brand new to the industry,
although I've been
in and out of gyms
and training for over 40 years.
I became a PT this year. So I had a
massive change of career early on in the
year,
had a very traumatic exit from a previous
career that I was in.
I've ended up in a right mess with that,
and I had to do some big
life-changing decisions, and I thought,
you know what?
This time of your life,
you're too old to go and find another job.
Work for yourself.
You're never going to do it
if you don't do it now, and go and
do something that you're absolutely madly
passionate about and have been
forever.
So yeah. So I thought, right,
I'm going to be a PT. That's it.
I want to live in a gym because I love it,
and that is my life.
So went and did that.
Best decision I've ever made, 100%.
Then it was like, right, okay, so how
are you going to make some money at this?
Because you need to start earning some
money.
And it's been slow,
and I've got a few clients.
I've managed to get myself a job in a gym,
which is great.
And I'm contracted in there.
I'm not working for them, which is lovely.
So I've still got my own time
and what have you.
Now I need to work on the online thing.
So I thought, right,
I'm going to start looking into this.
How can I make some money doing this?
It looks really easy.
All you need to do
is just video yourself
and throw it on there, and loads of
people are going to trust you
and think you're fantastic
and pay you loads of
money. [scoffs] Yeah.
[chuckles] If it makes you feel better,
I remember
seeing or listening to Lane Norton talk
about online coaching in
2014. I thought that sounds great.
And I went onto Facebook,
and I made a little image,
and I put a bit of text on it
saying, "Now taking online clients."
And the second I put it up,
nothing happened,
and I came to the exact same realization.
Now, it looks easy. It is easy
if you do it right.
They say the same about jujitsu.
Royce Gracie, 10-time world champion,
he goes,
"Jujitsu's easy.
You just got to do it right." So that's
not a bad thing
whatsoever.
Do you mind me asking how old you are?
I'm 56.
You look fantastic. So first things first-
Wow, I appreciate that. Thank you.
[clears throat]
Fifty-six.
There might be an element of you
potentially
insecure about the age,
getting into the industry and whatever.
100%. Yeah.
At the same time,
I'm sure you could probably
attest to this,
women probably between 48 and 60
who do need to train in the gym because we
could be looking at things
like
offsetting osteoporosis, sarcopenia.
We can be looking at the issues
that menopause are going to play as well.
They will much rather confide, talk,
and be coached by
someone of your age than they would anyone
else.
Yeah.
So I think that is a really important
thing to
discuss straight away.
Sorry to get straight into it.
Have you been through menopause?
No, that's all right. Oh my God,
have I been through menopause.
Have I been through it
and come out the other side.
But I also took a menopause coaching
course because I knew it was
going to be a big factor in this.
And like you said,
women 40 plus. At the gym
that I'm working at now, it's
called Transform Hub,
and it's
small group sessions type of thing.
It's a franchise.
And they specialize in people sort of 35
onwards, and all of the people that
are there in the groups that I'm
coaching, they're all in their 50s really,
50s, 60s, some of
them are in their 70s.
And I'm starting to really enjoy it
because I'm
relating to them. The women
are coming up to me,
we're talking about stuff.
We have really good banter. We're back
and forth.
We talk about menopause
because I've done it, right?
I've been there. I understand it.
I've been through it,
and I had every symptom
that there possibly was of it, so I
really struggled with it.
So I understood it very well,
and that's why I wanted to
take the course in it.
It's not the side that I want to focus on.
I want to focus on the PT side of it,
the coaching side.
But that menopause bit comes in.
Well, the reason
that it's one of the first things
that comes to mind is when it
comes to communicating with people online,
you could win over someone's
attention or build an element of trust
with the brand through
something that you're not coaching them
with.
So for instance, an example I would use
is some other people that train
jujitsu might have used my coaching app
because they
went, "Oh, I've got several PTs here,
but James trains jujitsu.
He might be better versed in balancing
weight training
and jujitsu training." So I'm not saying
we become the menopause doctor or the
menopause coach.
It could be one certain content bucket
that you could use
because if you were to explain to people,
because I'm trying to think
about those aha moments where people go,
"Fucking hell, I'm
so glad I discovered Vicky." It could be
that they discovered a menopause video
that wins them in,
and then it could be something later on
that potentially helps
them.
So that's one of the first things
that comes to mind.
And then the one thing I would say is,
let's build a
strong face-to-face business where you can
relax a bit, you can drop your
shoulders, and then
if I said to you it could take three
months to win an online
client,
let's make sure we're making enough money
in person so that that doesn't
worry or stress you out.
Yeah.
What was the industry you were in before?
I was in mental health. I worked
for a company that diagnosed ADHD
and
treated, treated and diagnosed ADHD.
So I was operations manager for a company.
It's been really traumatic.
I've ended up having to leave
that company because
I discovered that all of my pension
was missing.
Yeah. I'm owed so much money from them,
and I'm in the
process of a tribunal at the moment.
So that's been very, very stressful.
And I've not earned any money since
January, so
it's been a
tough six months. [chuckles] It
was a job I didn't want to leave,
if I'm honest with you. I really loved it.
I loved what I did.
I loved the people I worked with. It
was a very rewarding job.
And I'd been there for six years,
so it was quite a traumatic end.
Yeah. The guy that I worked for
was supposed to be a friend of mine,
and it just,
yeah-
Oh, no
... it's a mess. Yeah. [chuckles]
So as you may, maybe in two years' time,
we can look back at this as being
one of the kind of, quote-unquote,
"best things that's ever happened to you."
Yes.
I hope that is the case. Now,
I would say that at some part of this, we
do want to consider this to be a story.
Now, I'm not saying
that we go out onto social media
and we say, "Hey, my last
employer fucked me over,"
or anything like that.
Yeah. [chuckles]
When we do eventually start taking people
away from social media, I do think
this becomes a little bit of your story.
So already, if you
were to have a lead magnet, or we
were to take people
away from it, I think you could say,
"I'm Vicky.
I'm 58 for a personal trainer." Some
people might think, "Why did you get into
the industry at this age?" Well,
funny story,
everything was swept away from underneath
me. And you're going to show resilience.
You're going to show an element of grit.
You're going to show some of the traits
that people need in their coach,
because it
isn't just who's the fittest
and who's got the best rig.
There are other things there
that people need.
Especially if you
are probably going to end up with at least
25, 30% of the
women that you coach being probably
menopausal.
So they're going through some hormonal
shifts.
You can remind them one day, you go, "Oh,
but you've still got a fucking pension,
so back to the gym."
[laughs]
So there's going to be components of
that where, yeah,
I do think that is a little bit of your
story.
Have you ever read a book called "The
Obstacle
Is The Way" by Ryan Holiday?
No.
It's one I would recommend.
You get it on audiobook.
You probably listen to it through Spotify.
Yeah.
This is me counseling you now.
Okay. [chuckles]
Basically,
the whole premise of the book is
relying on stoics
and people over the years
that have often attributed
some of the best breakthroughs
that have ever happened in life coming
from a very
bad or traumatic thing that's occurred.
There's also
stories in there,
I haven't read it in years,
I'm probably overdue, of, I
think Abraham Lincoln was
really, really depressed.
And he accomplished a lot.
Not to say these are... But
when you read the book,
and you go through some of this
stuff, you go, do you know what?
You could be like, "I'm healthy.
I'm enjoying what I'm doing. I'm 58.
I'm winning in so many respects." So I'm
glad that already
you're quite positively spirited about it.
But I'm here like, let's make some money,
though.
Yes. [chuckles]
And this isn't like an evil capitalist
agenda either.
We are going to be helping you earn money
through creating value for people that
they're going to enjoy.
I know some people hate how salesy I am
with, like,
Nootonic and various different businesses,
but ultimately there's going to be value
that is created there.
So talk to me about, at the moment,
what is it you are selling
and offering at this gym?
So at the gym that I'm working at,
it's a little bit different because it is
like a group sessions.
It's not an open gym.
So here's the issue is
that I'm not going to pull any
clients from this gym.
They're not coming in
and I'm walking the floor and picking
up clients. I'm going in and I'm
coaching group sessions at certain times
of the day.
But he's paying me, it's not brilliant,
but it's decent money
that I needed. I needed to get an income.
I needed to start earning some money.
So I took that on. Now,
that's why he's paying me a better rate
than he would
normally,
because I've said he wants me there.
He absolutely wants me.
He knows I'm exactly the type of coach
that he needs there because of my age,
because I've done the menopause,
I've gone through all that.
And the clients that he has are
that age group, so I'm very relatable.
Plus,
I've got a lot of business background,
so this is why he wants me there, and
that's why he's paying me decent money to
do it.
But the difference I've said to him is,
"Don't forget, I can't pull any clients
from here.
I'm not going to get any one-to-ones from
here." It's not like an
open gym where I could go in and do that.
I have got access to another gym
that I can do that at.
They've said they're more than happy for
me to do that.
But at the moment,
I haven't got any clients from there.
So,
the amount that you're earning from this
gym, this facility at the moment, is
this enough to pay your bills?
Just.
Okay.
So would I be fair in saying we got our
head above water?
Just,
and it's literally just started last
month. Yeah.
Okay. So first thing, good.
Yeah.
Obviously, there's going to be anxiety,
alarm bells, whatever.
I feel very drawn to your journey already,
so don't worry, I'm not going to leave
you hanging after this call.
So we do need to start marketing that.
So the other facility, if you
were to take in clients and
train with them,
whereabouts in Manchester?
Altrincham, South Manchester.
So it's quite-
Okay
... an affluent area around here.
Is it far from Bury?
Yeah. Yeah, it is really.
Where's Bury?
Bury's more North Manchester, sort of.
Yeah-
I've only been maybe 5, 10 times.
There are some nice areas in Manchester.
I always thought that the north,
us southerners, we're bred to believe
that the north is a little bit...
But it's nicer than the flipping south
now. Okay, Altrincham.
Yeah. There are some really nice areas.
I'm quite close to the airport,
but it's more Cheshire, really,
so it's very
leafy.
Ooh, okay.
Yeah, it is a nice area. Yeah.
Okay. And another thing ultimately is
that people will choose you as a coach
because they like you,
and that's another important thing.
I'm already vibing a nice amount of
likeness from
this call that I think that
if we could get you in front of enough
people, that
people would potentially vibe with you.
And if it's from an area like that,
there's probably going to be people
that just
want casual training. There
are a huge amount of wealthy people
that will
go, "Yeah-" Vicky, I like the fact
that you're well qualified,
but I'm going to pay
you just so I fucking do it.
Yeah.
And they're the great ones.
They turn up in a Porsche-
Yeah
... "Do you want a coffee, love?"
Yeah.
"Do you want anything?" So we could tap
into those. Right.
So,
first things first,
the deal with the other gym.
So if you've taken a client
and you train them for an hour,
do you have to pay for
the session?
Yeah. So what they've said to me
is they're not going to charge me rent,
which
would normally be 600 a month.
Mm-hmm.
They're going to just charge me per
client,
£12.50 per client.
Okay. And,
have you got a rough idea of what you want
to
charge as an hourly rate?
Well, at the moment, in
that particular gym, the average is around
40.
It's about fair. Yeah,
I'd say that's pretty good for an average
PT session.
Yeah.
Now, in the onset,
how many hours are you doing with the
group coaching in the other gym, and is it
the same hours every day?
No, it's not the same hours.
I do have a month schedule, so I
know ahead what I'm doing,
and it's roughly around 15 to
18, 20 hours a week.
Oh, wow.
Yeah.
So it's pretty full on.
Roughly, when you were to break it down,
how much would that be an hour?
It's 30 quid an hour.
Okay. It's not terrible either.
So it's not terrible. Yeah.
No, that's pretty good. Okay.
So we would probably want to go for the
£40 an hour session if we were-
Yeah
... to take a client in a one-to-one gym.
Otherwise, and even then,
technically per hour,
you're going to be earning a
smidgen less than what you're doing at the
moment.
Yeah.
Which is, yeah, going to be something
that we could work around.
What would be your capacity of hours
that you could do in a week?
Would you be able to do 30 hours a week?
Oh, yeah.
Okay. So
if we could get you to do 30 hours at £40,
we'd see a considerable uptick where
you'd have a little bit of spare income,
and then we would really want to utilize
the online stuff to scale a little bit-
Yeah
...
and have some kind of surplus revenue so
you can start to save a
bit,
or at least keep your head above water.
With the tribunal you're going through
with the work situation,
you may not be allowed to talk about it,
but is it looking promising or-
It's... Yeah
... are you setting yourself up?
No, I don't think so. It's
clear the money was taken. It's
all documented.
All of the asking the questions,
the emails, the WhatsApp.
I've got everything documented.
It's all been uploaded. It's all gone.
The employment tribunal have agreed for me
to have a hearing,
so they must think
that I've got a decent case,
because they could've just turned
around and said, "No,
there's not enough evidence."
And I've had to do this all myself because
I couldn't afford a solicitor.
[chuckles]
Oh, God.
So thank God for ChatGPT, let me tell you.
He's helped me out a lot with putting
documents together.
[chuckles]
But is it looking hopeful? I'm
going to say
70%, yeah. But who knows?
I may have done it all for
nothing. It doesn't matter.
It's not all for nothing.
It isn't all for nothing,
because I need to be able to stop this guy
from doing it
again. This is my thing.
If I don't get a penny out of it,
I don't get a
penny out of it.
He cannot be allowed to do this because
he's done it
before, and I didn't know.
Fuck. And then, sorry to get personal.
Family situation, married?
Widowed.
Oh, God. I've set myself up there.
I do apologize.
You've properly set yourself up here.
[laughing]
Yeah, so very happily married.
Had a fantastic
marriage.
Oh, okay.
Married to the best bloke ever, yeah.
Lived in Canada for years.
Had a great life.
Very, very sadly, lost him
12 years ago.
So that was a dark time. [chuckles]
But thankfully,
had the most incredible support system
around me.
I've got the most amazing family. Oh,
my God.
Brought me back from Canada with my son.
And yeah, I
was just a mess for a year.
Family looked after me, took hold of me,
said, "Come
on,
we're going to sort you out." My son
was 19 at the time.
He said he wanted to go back to Canada,
so he went back to Canada.
And he's lived there ever since. So yeah,
I've been pretty much on my own.
[chuckles] But done it, survived it,
got through it, come out the other side.
Have some amazing memories of my husband.
They just make me smile. I was so lucky.
I was really, really lucky.
Such a great marriage.
But sadly, it wasn't meant to be forever.
So yeah.
It's...
Yeah.
Fuck.
This is the saddest call I've ever done.
[both laughing] But in the nicest way
possible,
I'm having a 24 hours from hell,
but I'm staying in positive moods because
so many people
have got genuine problems.
By the way, I'm not trying to steal
your thunder here.
I probably had three things
that happened that were really
annoying, let's say.
Yeah.
Then there was one
that just made me a bit anxious.
Someone saying something online
that just isn't true.
Oh.
But I can't really give it my energy
because that's what they want.
And then, today, imagine this.
I put Bill Withers'
"Lovely Day" on in my car, and I was like,
"I'm just going to put myself into a
good mood." I was like, "Do you know what?
I'm going to go wash my car."
And for the first time,
I must have got soap in the
engine bay. I'm driving down the road
and thought my engine was on fire.
And the amount of heart attacks
and anxiety that I've had in the last 24
hours,
I'm surprised I haven't had a heart
attack.
But I go home,
I had a nap with my fiancée, and I
was like, "Do you
know what?
Worse things have happened to better
people." And I'm
now in a good mood.
Oh, sorry. And I've just depressed you.
No. Because ultimately, I could sit back,
if we hadn't spoken two hours ago,
I could try and maybe have a little bit of
a
pity party that I'm having a bad day.
And then [chuckles] speaking to you-
[laughs]
... I realize my problems are so small
and inconsiderate. So-
[chuckles]
...
I'm really glad we're having this
discussion.
Oh, good.
Fuck. What does your son do?
Oh, God. Are you ready for this? So this-
Yeah
... is going to get you going and all.
So my son,
bless him, Ben, he's now 31.
Mm-hmm.
He went through a pretty traumatic time
prior to losing my
husband. [laughs]
Fuck.
So yeah. I lost him for a little bit.
He went off the rails, and
I mean off the rails.
Yeah. It was bad.
And then we lost Chris,
and things spiraled
even more. Then he went back to Canada,
so he was out of my
reach. I couldn't save him.
It got bad.
That was a long time ago.
I've got him back, finally. It took years,
[clears throat] but I
stood back, I didn't overwhelm him,
I let him find his
way, and he did, and I've got him back.
And he's the most beautiful human being.
I'm blessed to have him.
I'm so pleased, and our relationship
is unbelievable.
So he has dipped and dived in all sorts of
things his whole
life. He's now got,
and he's been doing it for a few years,
a job in a
hospital.
He is one of the porters in a hospital,
and I'm so glad that
he's got it because it's a really secure
job.
It's a great pension, it's great benefits.
He gets all his health benefits
and everything,
so he's finally found something
that is secure for him that he needed.
He met a lady three years ago,
four years ago,
a gorgeous girl from Ukraine.
She's had a very
traumatic experience in her life,
obviously having to leave Ukraine.
She was an angel sent to him from my
husband.
I am convinced of it because she
is the most beautiful person.
And yeah, he's happy, he's settled,
he's married.
He's good.
So I've got a great relationship with him
now, but that took a long time, and
that was hard. That was a really,
really tough time.
But we're really close now, which is good.
But he lives in Canada,
so I don't get to see him an awful lot.
[laughs]
Do you know whereabouts in Canada?
He's in Toronto.
Lovely. Great spot. Beautiful summers,
cold winters.
Great.
Great people, great food, poutine-
Wonderful
... Blue Jays.
Yeah.
[laughs]
Fucking hell.
You should be doing motivational speeches.
You're selling yourself short of doing
four by eight back squats.
[laughs]
Fuck me. But do you know what's good?
So we're going to start with PCM,
we're going to start with the personal
brand, and
I wonder where this takes you.
And I openly say this all the time that...
And do you know what?
Out of all the people to get one to one,
I'm so glad that it
was you.
[laughs]
[chuckles] Yeah. It's crazy. So
the brand building that we can do here,
I wonder if
even in five years' time if this
is continually what you do,
but either way,
we need to get this kind of set up.
Give me your Instagram.
Vicki J. Fitness Coach. Vicki with an I.
V-I-C-K-I-
Vicki J.
... J Fitness Coach.
I tend not to do too much
research before because I want to discover
this whilst I'm doing it.
So did you say V-I-C-K-Y?
No. V-I-C-K-I.
Okay. Oh, sorry. Oh, okay.
That's why you meant Vicki.
Yeah.
Vicki J. Fitness Coach.
Okay.
Straight away,
handle, Vicki J. Fitness Coach. Great.
I'm actually going to share this to my
screen for a second so that
people on YouTube should be able to see
it.
Okay, we're going to go here. Boom.
I always get a bit nervous
and anxious when I'm sharing my screen,
but it's okay.
So to begin with-
[laughs] Nothing dodgy
... 66 posts. The first thing,
you know I'm going to say it-
Yeah. I know
... it's just not enough posts,
but that's fine.
100 followers, give or take,
150 people that you're following.
Your bio, PT, online fitness,
menopause movement coach. Love that.
40 plus, want to feel strong, confident,
and sexy again.
I think that's a great tagline.
Realistic and manageable plans with real
results.
So really like the bio here,
think everything there is really good.
I'm going to open your Linktree into
another window.
And you have been active with what you're
doing.
And let's have a look at some of your
views for a second.
And by the way, anyone watching this,
I'm definitely putting this video on
YouTube,
and if I don't get you 10 flipping clients
from this video
alone, I'll start putting money behind it.
I'll start doing paid ads.
I'll pay for paid ads till you got a full
book.
Also, whilst we're here,
my event in September in London,
are you free that weekend?
Which weekend is it?
I think it might be the sixth and seventh.
I'm just going to double-check quickly.
Is it the Saturday, Sunday, fifth
and sixth?
Yeah, the fifth and the sixth.
Are you free that weekend?
I am.
Okay. I'll pay for you to come down.
I'll pay your travel.
It might be cheaper for you to flipping
fly.
I know what it's like from Manchester,
but no.
So
come to the event.
I'll get you a hotel as well because
it'd be cool to meet you,
it'd be cool to have you in the room.
It'd be cool to potentially even use your
story.
If you're free for that weekend,
I'd love to have you down.
Oh, wow. Thank you.
I will,
yeah, introduce you to the team
and everything.
There's going to be so many people in my
existing mentorship
that you will really get on with well,
one of which is called Katherine
Sargent. I don't know
if you've seen her online.
I follow her.
You two will get on like a house on fire
because she is also from the
north.
Yeah.
I think she's 46. She looks incredible.
She has absolutely smashed it. Okay.
Yeah. She totally smashed it. Yeah.
I follow her. I think she's great. Yeah.
For, I would say maybe
12 months it took for her content to kick
off.
I ended up showing her stuff to my story
as well because I was so adamant that
she could blow up, and she did. So again,
we've got
some things here that we're going through.
I actually love what you're doing.
I'm just going to have a quick look at
some of these.
So you're really in the right direction
creating content.
I would say that your captions
are probably doing too much of the
lifting.
So you're recording yourself,
you're putting a caption on top of that.
You're trying to communicate in the
caption, which is fine, but I would say
that we probably want to see more Vicky
than I want to read that. And also,
when people are scrolling through
social media,
they want someone to verbally connect with
them.
So we can get through some of this in a
second.
I love the fact you've got pictures here
working with clients.
Can you see my screen, by the way,
where I'm showing?
Okay. Yeah. I can see.
Yeah. Cool.
This one is what I like.
So you sit into screen here,
you start talking. I like that.
It's a bit of a visual hook. Big fan.
The hashtags don't do too much,
just to let you know.
That's one of those whispers of the, "Oh,
put a hashtag."
But this is probably the caption length
that I would like to get into.
Okay. Right.
And
we can move away from this,
but the fact is you've started with this,
this works.
It's worked for a lot of people.
I like the fact that you've got yourself
in the
gym, clearly a fitness enthusiast.
Has it ever been sport
or has it always been gym?
Horse riding.
That was in a previous life. I did
that for a long time.
I'm actually a qualified instructor as
well. Horse riding.
Really? Dressage, cross country?
Yeah. All of that. Yeah.
It's a bloody expensive habit, that.
Yeah. Hence I don't do it anymore.
[laughs]
My sister rides horses,
and then she now manages a polo
club, so-
Oh, nice.
Yeah. But
to be perfectly honest with you,
I'm not the biggest fan of polo.
I've worked in polo before.
Yeah.
It's the people.
[laughs]
I don't mind them hearing that.
Okay.
The people, unbearable, Vicky.
And my sister will kill me
for that.
I'll say not at the places she works.
Right.
[laughs]
Okay.
So you're showing up,
you're doing the reps,
you're doing things like this.
Okay, cool. I'm happy with this.
What I would love in your
bio is maybe to allude to the fact
that you are in the
area you're in.
Okay.
Because
you're getting 300, 700, 300, 350.
You're getting the views coming through.
Yeah.
One video's going to pop off,
as some of yours have got several thousand
before.
And when that video pops off,
let's say it gets 2,000 views,
if four might live in
the local area, someone might inquire.
And when they do,
or just say to them the truth.
"I'm just moving into a new facility.
You'd be my first client in this facility.
I'm very excited to get you the results
that you want," et cetera.
Now, from a branding perspective-
Yeah
... Firehorse Fitness,
talk to me about it.
So when this all happened earlier on in
the
year of me leaving the job that I was in,
the hype at the time was that it
was the new Chinese New Year,
Year of the Fire
Horse.
And it was just so happened to be the
date that I decided, "Right, that's it.
I'm having a new career.
I'm going into fitness training.
I need to have a name." At this point,
don't forget,
I've got no idea about online,
doing this. I'm just going to go
and be a PT.
I'm going to go and get 100 clients the
second I walk into a gym.
But I need to have a brand.
I have to have a brand.
What am I going to call myself?
I've no idea.
And it happened to be on February the
17th, the
day
of the fire horse, and I just thought,
bam, Firehorse Fitness.
Look at all the shit that goes on
that they talk about,
about the fire horse, about
it's this new beginning
and the powerfulness,
the power of the fire horse,
of the horse, and the horsey side of me.
And it just became, it was just a thing.
It came into my head and I thought,
Firehorse Fitness. I love it.
It's the Year of the Fire Horse. This
is a new start for you. Let's go for it.
I'm afraid I don't love it.
Okay.
And I'm sorry.
Because I haven't got a fucking clue about
the Chinese New Year. And again,
you don't have to take
any of my advice or we can argue.
And actually, so for instance,
we spoke to some branding companies for
Nutonic, and one of them said, "You've got
to get rid of the I." And we
were just like, "Fuck off.
Nah."
You can do whatever you like,
but you're not touching the I.
You can say to me, James, that's staying.
For me, my only concern is,
let's say we get
100 women in the local area,
and we ask them,
"What year is it in the Chinese New Year?"
It could lose them, and they're just
like, "I don't get it."
So it was less about the Chinese side of
it.
It was less about being into
that woo-wooey,
understanding what's going on with the
Chinese New Year.
We-
It was just-
I think you'll lose people on it.
I think that-
All right
...
the most important thing I want to say
is you are the brand. It's Vicky J.
Yeah.
I've been chatting to you for half an
hour.
I'm already one of your biggest fans,
and it has nothing to
fucking do with the fire horse.
[laughs]
All right? I'm going to tell you that now.
It has nothing to do with any of
that shit. I'm chatting to you.
I know your story.
I'm getting to understand you.
We've barely even got into the nuts
and bolts of half of this shit.
I'm like, "Come to my event. Hang out,
and if I don't get you the
fucking first..." After this call,
I'm going on my stories saying,
"If you live in
this area,
please contact this woman for coaching."
[laughs]
It's one of those things where I'm just a
little bit lost on the Firehorse. And
when I get to this Linktree-
Yeah
... I want to see Vicky J.
Okay. Yep
So, I'm founder at Firehorse Fitness.
Too much alliteration.
Yeah.
I just think you say, "I'm Vicki J."
[chuckles] "I've had a fucking crazy life.
I help women with this," or,
"I help..." Do you have any interest in
training men?
Yes. Yeah, absolutely. I just felt like
I needed to niche somewhere and-
Yeah
...
but I don't want to block out the fact
that I'm quite happy to
train men as well.
We're going to market towards women.
We're going to talk about menopause,
fat loss, toning.
Yeah.
We're going to talk about these things.
But men will come anyway.
Yeah.
And you know what?
You'll probably have some dude,
60,
might even have a wife,
but he just wants to hang out with a woman
who's not...
He might have a mental wife,
and he might just want to hang out with a
woman that's
not mental to do his reps and sets.
Or he might not love the idea of having a
dude
spot him for a back squat
or whatever it is.
Yeah.
So, I'm trying to load your website now.
Doesn't look like it's-
Well, it's not. Yeah. It won't.
I don't think it'll come up yet.
It just-
Why is it on the bloody Linktree, then?
I know. Sorry. I'll tell you why.
[laughing]
Because we're literally this week in the
middle of trying to get it up and running,
so it was just thrown on there.
But I'll take it back off.
Okay.
So really, I think that the WhatsApp,
so that
works. I'm messaging you now.
Okay.
I like that. I think that you just say,
"Message me on WhatsApp."
Okay.
So you've got... That's great.
I love the WhatsApp.
I reckon we click through to that.
Yeah, it's come through.
And I reckon you just say to yourself,
on your Instagram, where your Linktree is-
Yeah
... get in touch.
We open the Linktree,
we get rid of the other three menus,
and there's-
Yeah
... just a menu there that says,
"Drop me a message on WhatsApp."
Okay.
It could even say,
"Arrange a trial session." It could be
anything.
For me,
that's the strongest of all those options
there, is just coming straight
through to your mobile.
And in the nicest way possible, the
scale that we're at is going to be
that you can just give out your number.
I'm still using the same phone number
that I used in Fitness First back in
2017. It's fine. I put my number anywhere.
If I get any random phone calls,
I just block the cunt.
So,
let's dish that out. Let's use
that as kind of your first lead magnet.
Also, women around the age of
which you want to work with,
they'd probably much rather just drop you
a message,
go, "Hey, my name's Linda.
I need to drop a couple pounds.
I've got a trip overseas.
I'm going to Ibiza next year." Whatever it
is.
So-
Yeah. Okay
Okay.
I'm going to start taking some notes for
you as well whilst
we're on the call. I can do that separate.
So,
let's start planning out some of your
content that we're going to run with,
which I think could do potentially well.
So I'm just going to open a document
that I'm going to share with you
afterwards.
Okay.
And you'll notice on the top of my
document, I've put Vicki J.
I've not put Firehorse Fitness.
Okay, so, for the avatar,
we're going to talk today, let's go
women between 40 and 60. Like we
said, men are still going to come along,
they're still going to train, but every
time we design a video, the language,
the cadence, what we're going to do,
everything's going to be in line with
that.
Okay.
So let's go into some of their problems
that you think they have.
Okay. You want me to
reel some off, yeah?
Reel some off.
Okay. So [clears throat] majority are
the weight gain.
It's crept on. They haven't even realized.
[clears throat] Lack of confidence.
I was doing an orientation with a lady
last night, and
bless her, she's 38, she's
two young kids.
Without even realizing,
"I've put on four stone.
It's just crept on.
I've lost my confidence.
I won't even go out socializing
anymore.
I need to lose this weight to be able to
take the kids on holiday."
Massively a confidence thing, I think,
and I can remember feeling like
that myself
when I went through menopause.
And I didn't really put on much weight.
I put on a little bit,
but because I've always been into my
fitness, but
it was a confidence boost.
Losing your memory,
not being able to remember why you walked
into a room,
forgetting people's names.
All of those feelings
that just stopped you from being who you
were before, that confident person that
I've always been.
I can remember feeling like that.
So yeah,
massively the weight
mostly.
The confidence thing
is crazy because even myself, right?
I've been very open about the fact
that over the last two years,
I often will take
Mounjaro when I travel because otherwise I
just gain weight when I travel.
I probably gain five kilograms.
Yeah.
Now, so my fiancée, she's like,
"You look fine," but to me, I don't.
Mm-hmm.
And even the selection of T-shirts
that I will wear socializing will
change between 92 and 97 kilograms.
Right.
So that confidence thing is massive.
Yeah.
And a lot of people might look at me
and think that I don't struggle with
confidence or that I'm not insecure,
but quite literally, the color of
the rash guard that I wear to jujitsu
is dependent on my body weight.
So that-
Huh
...
the reason that we're kind of getting this
out there is that this is what we're
going to use to ideate some stuff. Okay,
let's keep
going. The kids on holiday one is massive.
Yeah. Massive.
I had another lady the other day who left
one of the sessions, and she was
going on holiday,
and she popped her head back into the gym
and shouted over, and she said,
"I just want to tell you that this is the
first time in my life I'm going to have
body confidence in a
swimsuit on holiday."
Okay.
That was
a massive moment.
She's 57-
And she looks amazing.
She's put on great muscle.
Her shoulders look great.
She looks fantastic.
And that absolutely made it for me,
that moment of her saying that.
The body confidence at 57,
that's the first time ever.
How incredible is that? Yeah, loved it.
So yeah, confidence, overweight,
fear of not being independent.
That fear of, in
another 20 years,
[sighs] I'm just not going to be able to
get myself up off the floor.
My kids are going to have to start looking
after me.
They're all things
that I just constantly think about.
My parents are incredibly active
and incredibly
independent. My dad's 88, my mom's 80.
My mom still works.
She's got a little rescue dog.
She works and takes him into the hospital.
She volunteers in the hospital.
She takes her little dog in because he's a
therapy
dog, and she takes him to go
and visit people.
They're an inspiration to me.
I want to be like that when I'm in my 80s.
I want to be that independent person who
doesn't require
their children to take care of them.
And yeah, so
working towards that.
Strength, bone health,
it's all of those things
that women do talk to
me about and say that they're ready.
They're just fed up of feeling the way
they do. Everything's hurting.
Joints are killing them. Their knees
are killing them.
Getting up off the floor,
picking up the laundry,
just everyday stuff.
Where is your stance on HRT?
Yeah, I can't live without it.
[laughs]
Cool. I like this. Team HRT.
Do you follow Dr Louise Newson?
I used to. I haven't for a while, but yes,
I did use to.
Is this some of the controversy online?
No, not really.
Okay.
I just-
Reading her book was a massive eye-opener
for me.
I actually-
Yeah
... I was in Dubai. I
was staying at the W.
I was traveling on my own, and I
was reading a book on menopause.
A woman swam past me,
and she [chuckles] goes, "I must say,
it's very nice to see a young chap reading
a book on menopause." And I
was like, "Oh, thanks." She was like,
"Why are you reading it?" I was like,
"Work."
But then what started as work
was then a bit of an obsession with the
fact that every
person has a woman in their life.
Like every person, mother,
sister, partner. And menopause is such a
gargantuan journey-
Yeah
... that people have to navigate.
Yeah.
And again,
I get called a misogynist online quite a
lot, and a sexist.
I did a fucking TED Talk on the menstrual
cycle.
So people, I'm like,
"You picked the wrong guy."
[laughs]
And
the menopause side of things,
the big thing for me is
that mental health battle
that occurs throughout menopause.
The average age of suicide in women is 53.
Yeah.
So these are all things
that we could bring into it.
So,
all right. So just quickly,
I've made a note of all of this stuff.
We're going to quickly put your content
into buckets, which I
talk about quite a lot.
Yeah.
And this is just going to help you with
the ideation side of things.
So we're going to go menopause as one/HRT.
The next one's going to be confidence at X
age.
The next one,
talk to me about your principles of
nutrition.
So for me personally, just been a
massive believer in protein. It's
huge, certainly for women of our age,
being able to
build muscle and maintain the muscle mass.
You've got to feed it protein.
And I've realized
that more so really over the last
few years, actually.
So coming out the other side of menopause.
It hadn't really been a major focus for me
during it, but coming out
the other side of it
and starting to realize
that building muscle is getting
really, really hard now.
It's not as easy as it used to be.
Back in my 30s, it
was quite easy to do it,
but now it's difficult and I've
got to
feed my muscles as much protein as
possible. So that's an important part.
And I think also for women who are quite
overweight, so you're looking at your two,
three, four stoners who need to
lose that.
Calorie counting,
at the end of the day,
it's what it boils down to.
Whatever you're putting in versus what
you're putting out.
But at the same time,
making sure what you're putting in
is the protein, because
it's super important.
What's your stance on GLP-1 medications?
What's your appetite like personally?
Answer me that first.
I eat like a horse. [laughs]
So the one thing is,
I'm not going to discredit your
physique or where you're at and say
that you didn't earn it.
One thing I would say is,
the GLP-1 medications,
I would never rule it out.
Age your friend is not your competition,
and
some women
cannot get away with eating-
Yeah
... quite so much. So,
I think there's like a liberating side to
it where if later on down the journey,
you say if my clients struggle with their
weight, I get them to eat high protein, I
get them to focus on their nutrition.
I get them to do this, do this, do this.
And if not,
I tell them to have a consult with their
doctor and they can seek
medical intervention that way.
In those affluent
parts of Manchester,
I guarantee they're probably dabbling
or dabbled
already.
I know plenty who are,
but I'm going to tell you now, I
truly believe there
is a place for the GLP-1s.
There absolutely is, 100%.
Right.
Because there's so many personal trainers
in denial that feel threatened,
that are like,
"You just need to work harder."
And these women,
they've been working hard.
They've got kids.
Yeah.
And also, some of them will go, "Look,
even if it's bad for me,
I just want to feel good in a swimsuit-
Yeah. [chuckles]
... before I fucking kick it in 30 years."
Yeah.
So okay. So we've got the menopause,
the confidence, nutrition.
But then back to the HRT. Sorry,
my mind just to jump around a little bit.
Yeah.
Talk to me about your weekly setup.
Do you go pouches, creams?
Have you got any injectables?
So I am weekly pouches twice a week.
I am progesterone-
Sorry, patches. Not pouches, patches
... patches. Yeah, patches
I'm looking at pouches in front of me
... pouches. Patches. [laughs]
Cool. Carry on.
Patches for estrogen. I
still have a coil for progesterone-
Yeah
...
but I also take progesterone orally
because I've got some
issues going on down here
that have been looked at, at the minute.
And I also take testosterone.
Amazing. How'd you take the testosterone?
Is that cream?
Yes.
The-
Yeah. A gel
So the cream... Do you know what?
I miss the cream. I'm on injectables.
I loved the cream when I took it,
because the only issue was
I'd take it and then train jujitsu,
and I was worried about it rubbing off.
I was actually worried-
Oh, yeah
... about not getting enough of it.
Here's a fun fact for you.
I would rub the cream on my scrotum to get
more absorption.
[laughs]
It's been studied.
And how was that? [laughs]
Yeah, great. Do you know what? So for me,
because you've disclosed a lot with me,
when I started TRT, it was my libido
that was a problem.
Right.
I could train rounds
and rounds of jujitsu. Could train.
My weight training fell by the wayside,
but my libido was the bit
that concerned me the most.
Right.
Now, I even opened a show in Dubai
and joked
at one point that I
was worried I might be gay.
So not that being a gay is a bad thing-
No
...
but I've just moved in with my partner
and the love of my life, so
I thought it was just what it
was like living with someone.
So I just assumed,
because I'd never lived with anyone before
in my life.
I had no idea what long-term relationship
was like.
Yeah.
But then when I started the testosterone
cream, my libido came back like
waft. And I was like, for me,
from a mental health
perspective as well-
Yeah
...
it wasn't the fact I was worried I
was gay. That's my joke.
But the worry was that-
[laughs]
...
I wasn't fulfilling my partner with the
sexual needs that she has.
It was all of those kind of things. So-
Yeah
...
it was very liberating for me to start
testosterone.
The reason I want to ask about this is, so
we're going to have these content buckets
that we've got here, but some of them
we can game the system a little bit.
So I've put menopause HRT,
I've got HRT protocol.
Let's go gym confidence for another.
So we've got five buckets
that I've written down.
Yeah.
Then I'm going to give you some videos
that you're going to make for me in the
next
week.
We might end up doing a call a week at
this fucking rate.
So,
I'll share with the document in a second,
but we're just going to run off the back
of it. So avatar, women between 40 and 60.
The problems, weight gain crept up,
lack of confidence, kids on holiday, et
cetera. So
looking at your content buckets,
which I've done menopause,
confidence at age,
nutrition, HRT protocol, gym confidence.
I'm going to
write out some hooks
that I think could work.
Now, the reason being
is once we get the hook right,
it's the first part of the
ingredient that we need-
Yeah
... to get seen more with people online.
Yeah.
So menopause HRT.
Did you say 58?
56.
56. I'm 56. Menopause.
How would you describe
menopause?
Would you say it was living hell?
At times, yes.
Yeah.
Living hell at times is what they
don't tell you to expect.
Cool. So
your video I
want in the next one, I've written down,
and these are just ideas to give you some
direction in which to go.
Yeah.
You sit it down, you go, "I'm 56.
Menopause was living hell at times.
Here's what they don't tell you to
expect." So that, to me, makes a
statement. People,
just by listening to that hook,
that first sentence, going to
get an idea about what the video's about.
Then people who are planning or
are going through menopause will stay.
People that aren't will leave.
And because you've only done 66 posts,
I want you to
think about this.
Instagram is going to be watching every
single person that engages with your
content and trying to profile them-
Yeah
... because ultimately it's going to go,
Vicky talks about certain things, certain
audience resonate with it. Over time,
YouTube as well, the algorithm's going to
learn what people like, what they don't,
because it's in Instagram's best interest
to pair content that people love with
people that love it.
So when I scroll at night,
I will watch tradesmen that
are really good at their trade.
The other day I was watching carpenters,
when
they get a plank to fit in the corner-
Oh, yeah
... how they use a protractor-
Yeah. [laughs]
...
to... My fiancée, I'm like, "Babe,
watch this." We're sat there watching a
carpenter use a protractor. Tiler,
people that do driveways
with resin, those kind of things,
I'm hooked.
Then fail compilations,
people slipping on ice,
people twisting their ankle on
a doorstep. To me, this is gold.
I love it.
So Instagram knows me very well,
but then it knows when I
wake up,
I need a bit of GB News to get my blood
pressure going.
So
the more we can feed the algorithm,
the more it can understand this.
So even the first few times you sit down
and you go, "I'm 56,
menopause sucks. This
is what they don't tell you to expect."
We've created that
curiosity where we
are also not just helping the audience,
we're helping the
algorithm know what we're talking about.
Then you can go into a direction
that benefits you and your brand.
So you could say,
[lips smack] hunger shoots up.
It is so important
that you have three pieces of fruit that
you chop up and put in Tupperware every
day, and you make sure you finish this
fruit without... I'm making this up.
Yeah.
Because the snacks, the cravings,
they come at crazy times, and
there's nothing you can do about it.
So you need to make sure you do that.
Three pieces of fruit,
put it in Tupperware.
You are not allowed to have a hedonic
snack throughout the day till you finish
that
fruit. Why?
Because the more fruit that's in your
stomach, the less of other things
that are less satiating.
The second one could be protein.
I made sure that I had 500 grams of
protein a day by,
it could be 500 grams of mince,
or it could be 300 grams of chicken breast
or
whatever it is. Be like,
"I've worked with so many menopausal
women,"
which is going to be your appeals to
authority.
That's how you kind of slide things into
sentences.
Yeah
Of all the women I've worked going through
menopause, those that have had a high
protein diet have never gone back.
And number three is going to be weight
training.
So many menopausal women start running,
they start doing things, and you're just
battling your hormones
and you're never going to win.
You could even say towards the end of
that,
if this stuff-- Well, actually,
that's just how we're going to bow out
after that.
But we want something in there
that you'll know better than me.
What would be a nugget of advice
that you would give someone
maybe of that avatar and they go,
"Do you know what?
Fucking hell, Vicky,
I really needed to hear
that today." What would that bit of
advice be?
[clears throat]
Honestly, if someone had said
to me when I was going through it
and I was really struggling,
this is not forever and there
is an end to it.
Because you feel as though, is this it?
Is this how I'm going to be for the rest
of my life?
Because I don't want to be this person.
That's perfect.
So you do your three benefits and you go,
"To all those women going
through menopause,
just let me tell you firsthand, this
is not forever.
It does get better. Stay with it." Boom.
So you've arrived on the scene,
you've captured menopausal women,
you've delivered
value, and then you've bowed out, which
is going to cause people to either want
more, to double tap, to maybe engage
or comment.
But for that subsection,
that's what I think would be a really good
one.
We're going to move into the next one,
which is confidence at a certain age.
And it could be something where we're
going to get footage of you training in
the
gym,
because if I get you in front of camera to
go, one of the hardest things to do
in your 40s and 50s
is to train in a busy commercial gym.
If we can show footage of you doing that,
you are portraying to the
person that it's possible.
Then once they've listened
and absorbed that
hook, you can then sit down and go,
"My name is Vicky. I'm 56.
I help people get more confident in the
gym.
Here's three or four things
that you can do to make your life
easier." Number one could be the goblet
squat.
You could say,
"There's a lot of young
testosterone-fueled men that are fighting
for the squat rack.
Here's a goblet squat I'm going to walk
you through, which is
the least intimidating squat
that you can do because you can just find
a kettlebell
and you could do these." I recommend most
of my clients do between eight to 12
reps, and they do it across four sets.
That means they're going to do eight to
10.
If you find it too easy, go up a weight,
whatever it is.
Then you go to the next bit.
You could go,
toning is a real big priority for women.
Tricep extensions can be incredibly
difficult to find.
I get my clients to do plyometric box
press-ups.
So you just find yourself a box
and you can pre-record all of this
footage.
And if you put your hands narrow together,
you're going to work the back of your
arms a lot better.
That's really going to help tone.
Then the next thing could be, rather than
getting too worried about certain bits of
equipment or queuing or waiting during
busy times. Here's a box step up,
here's a box step down,
here's a lateral lunge,
here's whatever it is.
And then you give those people those three
things and they
go, "Okay, cool."
That's really helped me. And again,
you could be like, "If you need help with
planning your training,
just drop me a message
or my WhatsApp's in the bio."
There's going to be another element where
straight away someone goes, "Oh, I've
always wanted to use a squat rack,
but it's always been intimidating.
You kind of spoke to me on a personal
level."
Mm-hmm.
Again, you're going to know
that better than me.
I'm just kind of rifting those ideas.
And then once you've got that idea,
you're going to be going to the gym
and filming that anyway.
So I'd love to see that. Also,
if you can film a wide shot of you doing
the group training classes, maybe
not so tight that you can recognize people
in it.
Right.
But even if we did a wide,
we could use that footage in hooks to go,
"I help women
become more confident for a living.
Here's three things
that really help." So what I want us
to get out of the hook
is just letting the women know
that watch the content,
what they're about to get.
Because sometimes I think the people don't
appreciate
that when we're talking to people in
content,
we're giving people the opportunity
to stay,
but also giving them the opportunity to
leave.
Yeah.
So for instance,
imagine you're on a first date with
someone, they sit
down and the man opposite just goes,
"I'm going overseas in six months.
I just want to have casual sex for six
months.
Be really romantic, go to the cinema
and cook each other dinner." It'd be
much better finding
that out at the beginning than it would be
in six months' time
when he goes, "Hey, I'm off."
There's almost like a lack of honesty
that people have.
Whereas if you could just establish
yourself in the beginning and go, "Look,
this
is what I'm about to help you with."
That's better than being
ambiguous and going, "Hmm, there
are three things that women could do,
and if
they were just to do this thing,
then they would find out
that they didn't have to
do the thing before." Because
if you don't capture anyone
and give them the
opportunity to stay,
everyone's going to leave.
Yeah.
Now,
next one here.
Nutrition.
We could go
talk about high protein.
I would love to see how much
protein you consume in a day. And again,
the hook would be,
I'm 56, post-menopausal,
and this nutritional
change helped me remain in shape,
and it's protein.
And in this video,
I'm going to show you how much I consume a
day and how much I
would recommend you consume a day to make
that post-menopausal exact.
So we're going to show, not tell.
And again,
sometimes I think showcasing
that it's not plain chicken and broccoli,
that
it is certainly cooked meals. That it
is like even a grenade protein bar
might sneak its way in.
[chuckles]
And when they see that, they go, "Oh,
Vicky is just having eggs on toast for
breakfast. She's having some mince
and vegetables for lunch with
some rice or whatever it is." Just by
showing people that,
I think that'd be really, really good.
Okay.
There was a study that came out this
week about
overfeeding carbs versus fats.
It might've been Menno Henselmann,
it might've been someone else.
When you spot these things come out
and people talk about these things,
I think you
should get Instagram edits
and green screen yourself.
And maybe even you
could take that information
and repurpose it for your demographic.
So you could go Menopausal women for years
have been told that
carbs are the enemy.
But this study right here,
pointing at the green screen behind
you, actually shows
that overfeeding carbs has a better impact
on body composition than fats.
So what does that mean?
Then the next scene could be you in front
of your food, in your
kitchen, whatever it is,
and just explaining to people, "This rice
isn't the enemy,
these vegetables aren't the enemy.
It's actually the butters, the oils.
It's going to be the
sauces. It's going to be this."
I'm not saying these are bad,
but I'm saying you need to fill yourself
up and
satiate yourself. Don't be afraid of rice.
Don't be afraid of potatoes.
Incredible nutritional benefits here.
Not to mention fiber, which
is great for our health.
And so that when [clears throat] the woman
walks away from that video, they go, "Oh
my God,
Vicky just helped me have a better
relationship with carbohydrates." I'll
never forget a piece of content I saw
that told me that sweet potatoes are no
healthier than a normal potato. I,
in fact, wrote a blog about it in
2014,
and it was my most viewed blog ever
because people were sharing
it, and I called it Save the Spud.
So even though it
seems like a kind of
a weird conversation,
every piece of content has the ability to
change
someone's life forever.
Mm-hmm.
Then I tell you, again,
sorry, I could do this for hours.
I'm going to share my screen.
Have you heard of a guy called Ben Yanes?
I've heard of the name.
I talk about him a lot.
That's probably where I've heard it then.
Yeah.
So this guy-
Oh, yeah
... makes amazing content.
And I would suggest you follow him,
but sometimes he shows movements in the
gym that I've never really considered
before.
Like he did one here about Conor McGregor
tearing his ACL during the
fight.
Yeah.
And he goes,
"Do you know what probably happened?
Who fucking cares?" He's like,
"He landed on his knee, and it went pop.
It wasn't the medial rotation,
it wasn't the transverse this.
It wasn't that, it wasn't this." He goes,
"The guy jumped, the guy landed, the knee
went, game over." So,
there's one video in particular
that I watched.
Well, first of all,
he did a video not too long ago.
Big love to Ben Yanes.
I'm not probably going to find it.
He did a video not too long ago where he
said,
"Why is it that some pulleys in the gym
are easy and you do 20kg fine?"
Oh, yeah.
"Other gyms, it's really difficult,
and then other gyms it's even different to
that." And then he goes to explain how
there's single pulleys, double pulleys,
and
triple pulleys, and how the weight
is divided. But I never knew that.
10 years in the gym, never knew that.
I watched that video.
I just assumed that Techno Gym did it
different to fucking-
Yeah
... Hammer-
...
and to be honest, I didn't care. But
that one video changed my life
forever because I never looked at a pulley
the same. I now understood it.
But he did another one where he gets a
bench.
Yeah.
He sets the back of the bench to about 45
degrees, then puts it up to a dip
bar.
Yeah.
I was like, "Where's he going with this?"
He puts his toes back on the bench
and does slow, controlled dips whilst
keeping his torso at an angle
which remains consistent so he can keep
that tempo and time.
It just stabilized the dips-
Yeah
...
so that he could get a better contraction.
And I was like, boom, took the bench,
went and did it.
[chuckles]
So if you go through his content-
Yeah
... you're not going to steal it,
but-
Yeah
... your hook could then be
screenshot, green screen.
I saw Ben Yanes do this exercise,
and I wondered whether a woman who's
46 could do it and feel it. Or I'm 56,
I saw
this exercise, I wanted to give it a go.
This is what happened.
Because then women who
are also within the similar range
are going to go, "Wow,
that looks like an interesting exercise."
You could go away, try doing the dips or
pick an exercise that he does.
Then you could explain to your avatar,
"Hey,
this is going to help us build muscle in
the back of our arms.
This is going to help us have firmer legs.
This is going to help us
with whatever." We're now taking a concept
to someone else.
We're giving him the credit-
Yeah
... where credit's due,
but we're also using that as a hook to
win over the women in
which we need to talk to.
Yeah.
Do you know how to use a green screen?
So I, at the moment, use Edits-
Yep
... for my videos. The only thing I'm-
I'm just releasing an Edits course-
Oh, wonderful
... and it'll be added to your
dashboard from what you bought. So
when you're on
your Edits screen here,
I'll show you in a sec.
There-
Okay
... it says Music, Green screen, Timer,
Speed.
Yeah.
You press it,
and it comes up.
Yeah.
And then you just put an image behind.
So you can either screen record Ben Yanes,
et al.,
whoever it is. You can take a screenshot,
and then you can just
use that because green screening works
really well because people get curious
without you having to say anything.
They go, "Oh, what's she talking about?"
Yeah.
Edits. Go on.
The thing I wasn't sure about,
but you've just explained it then actually
without
realizing, was how do I record him?
But you just do a screen record whilst
watching it on Instagram,
yeah?
Or I shouldn't tell you this because it's
illegal, but friends of mine,
they type in on their browser,
Instagram Reel
Downloader,
and then they go down to one called Snap
Insta,
which is kind of purple. Then they,
my friends, put the URL
in and then download a high-quality
version of that reel.
So technically, I'm not sure
if you're supposed to do that,
not that anyone's really going to take you
to court for it. Just credit them.
And I don't see-
Yeah
... an issue in that. And then
if you're worried,
just put them in the caption and
show them love kind of thing. So,
with that side of things,
I think reacting to stuff
is probably going to see a bit of a
comeback
again with how easy that they've made
that in Instagram edits.
Yeah.
Now, the next one in
which I'm thinking about,
let me go back to the document for a
second. The HRT protocol.
[chuckles]
I think you could really bust down
some myths here. So
these are my estrogen patches.
I wouldn't survive without them.
This is my testosterone cream.
[chuckles]
And you could just say
After menopause,
I needed to feel myself again.
Testosterone and estrogen makes me feel
amazing.
Oh, and I actually take progesterone.
There's a lot of stigma surrounding HRT.
I just wanted to let you know
that there is a life after menopause.
The testosterone's really helped me with
my lifting, my muscle mass, and my sex
drive.
The estrogen's helped me with muscle
soreness, and it also helps with my
bone density.
And there could even be a reel in this
where you go,
"This is an estrogen patch
that I've taken since I've gone through
menopause."
Estrogen often gets a bad rap,
but it's responsible for
bone density, muscle soreness, fatigue,
brain fog.
Bodybuilders
have to be really careful
when managing their estrogen.
There is a drug called Arimidex or
Letrozole, and when men aromatize.
Do you know about this?
No.
So let's say I'm taking testosterone,
which I am.
Take about 140 milligrams a week. If I
was to go up to
200, 250, 300-
Yeah
... I know that I would start aromatizing,
where my body would convert the excess
testosterone into estrogen.
I'd become very estrogenic.
Okay.
I once did a cycle with a mate,
and I never knew how much we were taking.
He was just jabbing me up.
And because my body fat level
was higher than his, my
face went puffy as,
and my blood pressure was awful,
and I was holding so much water,
and my estrogen was the problem.
And when I came off cycle,
I looked so much better.
But bodybuilders,
they can worry about the estrogen helping
them develop, or
helping,
causing them to develop gynecomastia,
like breast tissue.
Yeah.
So to stop that in its track,
they take Arimidex or Letrozole,
which shuts off their conversion to
estrogen, but it makes them feel like shit
because they pretty much go through a
man's version of
menopause.
Yeah.
And they don't realize how much they
needed the right levels of estrogen.
So there's your little lesson. See, look,
I've now changed your life forever.
Yeah.
This is supposed to be about you this
call.
[laughing]
So
having those things as props I think could
be very valuable-
Mm-hmm
... because again,
women can then comment and go, "What?
So you take testosterone?" And you go,
"Yeah, I take a cream.
It's naturally absorbed.
It doesn't shut down my endogenous
production. It really helps me with X, Y,
Z."
What would you say
from those drugs,
I kind of put the words in your mouth,
how have they helped you?
[chuckles] So estrogen,
for sure with the brain fog,
with the night sweats.
Oh my God, the sweating was unbelievable.
Then I didn't start taking testosterone
until probably about four
years ago,
and the night sweats had come back.
So everything had settled. It
was all good.
And
the really bad hot flushes came back
again, and the brain fog started to come
back. So I went and had my levels tested,
and the
NHS said,
"We're not giving you testosterone." I
said, "But I think I need it
because I've done a bit of research on
it." They went, "No.
We can't give it to you.
You have to buy it privately." Then I went
to see a
gynecologist because I had some issues
going on.
He was fantastic. And I said, "Look,
they won't give it to me.
Can I please have it?" And he said, "Well,
the only reason that they'll give it to
you is if you say you've got a low
libido."
Actually, I didn't have.
I've been very lucky with that.
However, I said, "Well,
I can tell you that I have then, if
that helps." And he
said, "Yeah, that's fine. You've told me.
Here you go." And he prescribed me
testosterone.
So now I get it,
and it's massively helped me with the
night
sweats. They've stopped again.
The brain fog has stopped again. I'm going
off-piste a bit here. Creatine. Oh my God.
Well, that's a life-changer
for me.
How is it? Tell me about that.
Well,
first of all, muscle mass,
it's incredible the difference it's
made to me.
All these years of struggling to be able
to keep
muscle, and having to, like I said,
plow myself full of protein.
Started taking creatine, and it was
suddenly fantastic.
Now I've got really good muscle
definition.
But also, the brain, that
sluggish,
that feeling of I haven't got any clarity.
I'm struggling to remember words.
I can't think of what it is
that I'm meant to be doing.
And the creatine,
since I've been taking that,
I feel like that's been a massive
game changer.
So the first iteration of all of these
pieces of content I want to make,
usually my golden rule
is don't talk about yourself.
But-
Yeah
... in this scenario,
because I think menopause in this stage in
your life is such
an important journey,
I think people do care about your
journey.
The wording I would like to play around
with a little bit.
So the first iteration,
"I started taking creatine.
It changed my life in my 50s. This
is why." But then the other reiteration of
that
would be, "If you're in your 50s
and you're not taking creatine, this
is why I'd
suggest that you should." Then I want us
to kind of A/B split test that to see
which one performs best,
because ultimately one will, and I
don't know would be the answer of
which one's going to do better there.
Yeah.
The creatine thing there.
And the crazy thing is, right,
when I'm helping you script these
videos,
the only thing I really want us to script
is the first 10 to
15 seconds. So whenever I do adverts
for, well, for anything,
I script the first 15 seconds.
Yeah.
Then I just say what I need to say,
and then I'm out.
So I don't think we need to have a
teleprompter.
I don't think we follow a script.
The main strategic thing here is
that we get the hooks good enough
that we establish, we win someone over.
We get them to drop their shoulders so
they can listen.
Then, yeah. So the buckets I've given you,
I've got your WhatsApp now,
so I'm going to send you this over as
a link that you can access.
I also want you to use this document.
So if you put your notes in here,
I'm going to check back in here
in the next few days. We're not done yet,
by the way. I'm just giving you that.
Just let me double-check something on my
end
Yeah, we've got
time. Got about half an hour left.
As long as you have as well.
I have. Yep.
Cool.
And this doesn't have to be the last call.
I'm invested now.
I'm invested in this. Okay.
So from a social
perspective,
I think we can start getting out content.
I would like to see it on a daily cadence
if possible.
Yep.
Now, this is the rule, Vicky.
I don't care if it's good.
I care that it's done.
Yeah.
Even if it's an image,
whatever, one a day. I don't see
a reason as to why we can't do one a day.
Every one is an opportunity.
I
just want to get in a cadence where you go
to bed at night, and it feels odd if you
haven't done a piece of content yet.
And I just want to get
that creative muscle twitching.
And your funnel is going to be very
basic from here. The call to action
occasionally in reels, in the captions,
or even verbally said
is,
"Click the link in my bio to get in
touch." They're going to click the link in
your bio.
It's going to say to your WhatsApp.
Drop me a message on WhatsApp.
Then we're just going to look at the
funnel as in content posted, inquiries,
and
DMs.
Let me
quickly go back to your Instagram as well.
So we're just going to clean
that up a little bit.
On your
bio,
we might have to shorten it a little bit.
Let's have a look.
Vicky J
Fitness.
Is there a Vicky J Fitness
and Vicky J Fitness Coach?
Oh, is there?
Yeah, there's a Vicky J Fitness as well.
Wow.
But they've only done 57 posts,
and you've got more followers.
So-
Cool
... we've just got to make sure
that they don't-
Yeah
... and [inhales] we could change
it in time to
Vicky J.
What was the area you live in called?
I'm in Altrincham. Well, I'm in Hale,
actually, which is even posher.
Okay.
So I'm going to put this in your notes as
well.
To do.
Change bio, include location, call to
action is going to be a click link,
and the WhatsApp button is going to say,
"Get
in touch"
or
"Message me"
"Book a free trial class."
Could even have some tongue in cheek there
and say, "Look, I don't bite.
Just book in." And occasionally,
I reckon one of your videos should
be, "Let's book in a class.
Let's do that."
So the next thing we have
is the online side of things. Now,
like I said to begin with,
I think that the funnel solves problems,
get in touch.
And
the way we're going to run with this,
I think, is you are
always just asking women to get in touch
with you to see if you can help.
And the first thing I really said to you
on this call was, "How can I help?"
And you just say to them,
"How can I help?" And they go,
"Okay, I want to lose fat.
I want to do this," whatever.
Now, in the onset,
whatever you feel more comfortable with,
because you've got a vibe to you,
you could just jump on a call with them.
And it's not a sales call.
Yeah.
It's you just jumping on saying,
"How can I help?" And I think
I'm a good judge of character,
but I reckon there's even a part of
you that would sit on a call with a woman
for 20 minutes, half an hour, map out her
next six months.
I would do this with your diet,
I'd do this with your calories,
I'd do this for your training.
Then towards the end of it, you go,
"If you want me
to take full control of that,
it will cost this much."
And some people will
say yes, some people won't.
I don't think many women will waste your
time, whereas-
Mm-hmm
... the time wasters
are usually like the 22-year-olds that go,
"How much?"
And then as far as a weekly cost,
I would say we could mimic your hourly
rate to begin with.
And again,
we can always move north with prices.
We can't always move south.
So I would say that maybe we look to £40 a
week, and
we can start real basic with the online
stuff.
Yeah.
We can
contact and communicate via WhatsApp.
You say to the ladies in there,
"Send me a voice note, dictate,
message me, send me a video note,
whatever you need."
Mm-hmm.
You kind of use WhatsApp as the primary
means of communication.
Then you can even say to them,
"How best would you like to receive your
workouts?" Because some of them may be
wanting to use apps, there's Everfit,
Trainerize, whatever.
Yeah.
But then some of them also might just be
like, "Look, this overwhelms me.
I don't want to do that."
Yeah.
And you could even say, "Right,
I'm going to put everything into an Excel
spreadsheet,
going to make it look all friendly."
And then you could even
screenshot it, print it, whatever it
is for that person.
Here's a document. And again,
if you're using ChatGPT, you could go,
"Here's a
program that I've written my client.
Can you make it look nice
and put it into a format
that they could print in
A4?"
Yeah.
They might want to print it in A4,
take it to the gym, and use a biro.
And then at the end of the week,
you can say,
"Just take a picture of both your
programs on your phone, send it back,
and I'll change your program for next
week."
And that program could say sets, reps,
difficulty.
Or you could even say,
reps, set, weights that they've chosen-
Yeah
... perceived difficulty-
... notes.
Yeah.
And they might scribble,
this one really sore.
This one felt a bit easy.
Yeah.
This one felt a bit hard.
That first onboarding call, you'd say,
"When I write you
a program, I'm going to send it to you.
It's up for you to find a difficulty of
seven out of 10." And this is me getting
into PT mode now.
I'm not sure how you do it,
but I would just say RPE online is
your best friend,
the rate of perceived exertion.
Yeah.
You just say to the ladies like, "Hey,
I'm not going to tell you what you're
going
to lift. You're going to tell me,
and then we're going to work through what
it was
and how difficult you found it,
and we're going to work on a week-by-week
basis."
Then basically in the onset,
each woman probably
is going to take an hour of your time,
so you're going to get a
true £40. But then week two, week three,
week four, let's say we
do a four-week rotating cycle.
They can pay you weekly,
or they can pay you monthly.
Again, I would just say to them,
"However you want to pay me, let me know."
And just say to them as well, "Hey
If you do 10 weeks and the
11th-week payment goes through,
and you decide you don't want to do it
anymore,
just let me know.
I'll just send you the 11th week back.
Yeah.
You just say, "Look,
I'm chill." You also go heavy on the
guarantee.
You go,
"If you decide to start working with me,
you're covered with the guarantee
the full duration that I'm coaching you.
If in four weeks' time you don't feel like
we're making progress, just let me know.
I hit refund." Just being chill-
Yeah
...
I think is one of the biggest superpowers
in sales, where whenever I'm
promoting something, even on a webinar,
I'm like, "Guys, if you don't like it,
I'll
just put the money back in your account."
I've got enough people that hate me in
the world. I do not need unhappy clients.
So the same can go for you.
And then these ladies can go to the gym,
and I didn't appreciate this till maybe
two years ago.
My business partner literally hired me a
coach because I just wasn't
using the ones in my app.
And just knowing that someone out there,
I've
never spoken to the guy,
never done a call with him,
never voiced noted.
I haven't even got his number.
He just sent me an Excel spreadsheet on
email, and
I've sent it back when I was done.
And for years he was my coach, and it
was great,
and I was progressing in the gym,
lifting the biggest weight ever.
There was even times I looked at my
program, and I was like,
"Either this guy has
no fucking idea who I am,
or he thinks that I'm going to perform
really well this
week." Then I would smash the set
and go fucking hell.
I dig it, yeah. [chuckles]
It doesn't matter.
So then you just keep it real simple with
that.
If I was you, I would put in...
You could even
put Firehorse into their name on WhatsApp.
And as you build that list up, 5, 10, 15,
20 women, whenever you type
Firehorse into search,
just go to the last communicated with
person and just check
in. Now,
you can open your laptop in the evenings,
check in with your clients,
"Hey,
how are you going?" You can put all the
women into a group.
Yeah.
"Hey,
how are you doing this week?" Whatever it
is.
The content for me
is 80% to 90% of this entire
ecosystem.
There's going to become a time where you
could do, say you do a real Nit
Bangs testosterone, could be the patches,
could be the cream, could be the gym
confidence, whatever it is.
If we start pumping that out,
you just say,
"If you want to work with me,
click the link in the bio and get in
touch." That's where I think it doesn't
need to be complex.
We don't need to worry about emails too
much. We don't need to worry about that.
That's where I got a little bit lost in
the
course. It was like, "Oh my God,
I've got to try and grab emails off here,
and I
haven't even got anybody yet.
Hang on a minute.
How the hell am I going to do that?" Yeah,
this sounds way more a little
calmer, a little easier for me to,
at this stage, be able to
manage. Yeah.
And then there's going to come a time
where you're at 4,000 or 5,000 followers,
you're doing 20, 30 hours in-person,
you're doing 10, 15 hours a week
online. You're gasping for air,
and you're thinking, "Holy fuck,
how do I turn
the tap off on this?"
And then we might want to create a product
or a
system or a training program,
and we might want to productize something.
That's where we go, "Okay,
I'm going to need to scale this, and
I'm going to,
instead of asking people to click on the
WhatsApp, because I can't
really take any more people on,
I'm going to say to them, 'Hey,
I've created this
digital asset,'"
which I know you've already done because
I've seen it on your
Linktree, and every person that gets it
is going to give you their email address.
Yeah.
And then you're going to create this
backlog of emails so that when your
session amounts dip, which they will,
there's fluctuations that go through the
year.
People drop off, people will come on.
You can just pop out an email going, "Hey,
I'm looking for four more ladies to join
the program. It's £45 a week.
If you're interested, let me know."
Or you might
productize a 10-week training holiday
confidence program
where it's £99, it's a one-off cost.
You get to buy the program,
but once a week they get to jump on a
group coaching
call where you could then potentially sell
in
150 women at £100, you make 15 grand,
and you've just got
to jump on a 90-minute call once every
Wednesday night for the period of the 10
weeks. And then what's that? 150 at
£100, is that 15 grand?
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
Yeah. It'd be 15 grand.
Yeah.
Then the four weeks, you're looking at
four grand a week. Sorry,
10 weeks for what?
£1,500 a week-
Yeah
... £1,500 a call. So yeah,
that's where you would open
and elicit the scale element to it.
Right.
But we need to get the followers up-
Yeah
...
because to have 2,000 people on your email
list, to sell
150 spots,
we might need 2,000 on the email list.
To have 2,000 on the email list,
we might need to have 10,000 followers.
Yeah.
But the most important thing here for me
and for you is
to have head above water-
Yeah
... pay your bills,
enjoy what you're doing-
Yeah
... and gamify this process.
The views at the moment are like 300, 400,
which isn't
bad. They're going to go to 500, then 600.
You're going to get better.
You're going to become more proficient.
You're going to level up with it,
and you're going to become a scientist in
seeing what's working and what isn't.
Yeah.
And there's no way Instagram knows your
perfect
audience yet. But in 100 to 200 posts,
it really will.
Yeah.
There's
a guy,
I'm going to share a post about it later,
called Julian,
who is an S&C coach.
He's in my mentorship.
And he is putting out really good content,
and he was on
1,000 followers. And actually,
if I jumped on the call with him like I
did with
you,
there wasn't much things I could tell him
to do better.
I had to just say to him,
"I need you to keep going."
And I haven't heard from
him in ages, and I was worried
that he'd maybe quit or given up,
and he just posted
yesterday saying he's at 10,000 followers.
Oh.
The gap is two years of work to get to
1,000,
then boom,
you're at 10K within a few weeks.
There was a chick called Olivia in the
mentorship.
She was at 3,000 followers.
The next thing I know, she's at 10K.
I said to her,
"You're going to be at 50K within a
month." Within three weeks, she
was at 100K. The levels
that this literally moves, it's going to
feel like nothing happens,
then everything happens.
Similar to, I'm sure
that with many endeavors in life,
like a spaceship taking off.
I don't even think it's true,
but 90% of the
fuel is used in the first 10% of the
journey.
Mm-hmm.
If I can get you in a position
that you enjoy creating content, we
are working
towards goal one, which
is going to be you're going to wake up,
or you're going to
have a random stranger on the internet
message you inquiring about coaching from
content- That's going to motivate you
and gas you up so much-
Yeah
... to post more.
Yeah.
Then you're going to get some more in
there.
Then before you know it,
you're going to get on your first call
with someone, and
you're going to close them for a sale.
Then that's going to motivate you to
create more content.
Yeah.
But zero to one is the biggest battle here
that I
see.
Yeah.
I would love a piece of content that's
shot during the day,
and then maybe another post
that goes out in the evening,
maybe whilst you're just
sat on your sofa or something like that.
One a day, great.
Two a day, also great. Now tell me,
what platforms are you posting to?
So Instagram,
and then it goes directly onto Facebook.
There's a Facebook page as well.
And then I've
been doing TikTok as well.
Fantastic.
Are you on LinkedIn?
I have got a LinkedIn, yeah.
I've got a profile that was from previous.
I haven't got a new one for me now.
Let's use it.
Okay.
Let's tell people about your change in
career, change in profession.
This is what I'm doing now.
Okay.
And let's post. I believe, and I know,
that
LinkedIn is about to heavily reward video
content.
Okay.
So they're moving that way. Even
when you go to upload on LinkedIn now,
there
is a different tab where it used to be
like a media upload, photos and
videos. It's now videos and photos
are two separate areas.
So I would say that signals to me
that there's an algorithmic shift,
that videos and photos
are going to live on separate algorithms.
Right.
And I'm already starting to see more
videos come up in the feed on
LinkedIn.
Okay.
So if you're going to go to the effort of
creating a banger video-
Yeah
...
I don't see why we wouldn't put it in
multiple places.
Sure.
Now, with the last five to 10 minutes,
what questions do you have?
[sighs]
And you've got my number now.
Yeah.
And
should you have questions, come to me
and ask me. If you have any queries.
If you have a big issue as well,
we can just jump on another call,
because I think
for this video, if you're happy for me to,
I'm going to chop the ends, and I'm
going to put it on YouTube.
Yeah. Great. Happy to.
Do you mind if I ask-
Yeah
... what happened to your husband?
Mm.
Well-
You don't have to tell-
No, I'm more than happy to share it.
It's quite a traumatic, long explanation,
but I can
shorten it down.
So he was 44, very
healthy. Like super healthy.
I worked in a hospital at the time in
administration,
and I happened to bring home one day a
leaflet that was
just on the side and brought it home,
sat it down, and it was regarding
bowel cancer,
symptoms of.
And he must have picked it up at some
point, looked at it, and
then we went on holiday.
We came back off holiday, and he said,
"I've got something
to tell you. I've got some symptoms.
I found them on a leaflet."
I said, "Okay. What are they?"
Symptoms of blood, et cetera. La, la, la.
Luckily, I worked in the hospital,
got him seen straight away, and within two
weeks,
he was in for surgery for bowel cancer.
Now, that's not what took him.
So he had a chunk of bowel removed. He
was then
given
an ileostomy bag temporarily whilst
everything was being
fixed.
Massive, huge scar. Huge,
great big opening in his
stomach.
Didn't heal very well.
Took a long time to heal.
Then he had the ileostomy reversed,
sewn back up,
everything looked good,
should be full recovery, shouldn't be
life-changing,
and everything should be great.
He was, at the time,
worked for the Ontario Ministry of the
Environment, and he was
a boat captain on the vessels
that go out testing the
water in the Great Lakes. Great job.
Due to go back to work,
but didn't feel great.
A few months later, back
and forth to hospital
because just wasn't feeling great.
Started to lose a lot of weight.
Got very thin. Very poorly.
Long story short,
after seeing a number of different
specialists for a number of different
things, took him back in early September,
and
they sent him home again.
Couldn't find anything.
Called us the next day and said,
"The blood test has revealed that there
is sepsis.
Bring him back in immediately." Took him
back in.
The sepsis had affected his heart,
and it had destroyed his heart valve,
his mitral valve.
So he was in hospital for a week having
antibiotics to try
and get rid of the infection before they
could do a
mitral valve replacement in his heart.
So he'd already had massive bowel surgery.
Now he was having heart surgery.
So they took him in,
and they replaced his valve
in his heart.
And he came out of that surgery,
and they said it all went well.
There was a little bit of complication on
the table, but it's fine.
There should be a full recovery with this.
However, it is life-changing.
The chances of him going back to his job
were
slim.
He came out of there. He
was in hospital for a week
recovering from this heart surgery.
And on the day that we
were due to come home and be discharged,
and he was
ready to come home. He was fed up.
He'd had enough of being in there.
And on that day,
we're ready.
We're waiting for the doctor to come in to
sign the discharge
papers. I was in the room with him.
He wasn't feeling great.
I asked him to lie down on the bed.
He lay down on the bed.
As I'm sat there with him getting him
comfortable, he had a massive
bleed on the brain.
Doctors came rushing in, took me out.
They took him away.
All my family were in England.
[chuckles] His family were in
Canada, so obviously everyone arrived.
They came out to me about an hour later
and said, "We've managed to
stabilize him." They put a-
A valve in his head to drain it because
the bleed was
massive on his brain.
They told me that hopefully there should
be a recovery.
I was told lots of different things by
lots of different doctors, and it was a
very complicated time because some said he
would survive, some said he wouldn't,
some said he'll be on life support
forever.
It was a terrible 48 hours.
And then,
eventually I managed to get all my family
there,
and he was on life support,
and they asked me
a question that you don't ever think
you're going to get asked, and that is,
"When
would you like to turn off the machine?"
Fortunately, I'd got all my family there.
My mom and dad were there,
my best friend was there,
obviously my son and all of
Chris's family were there. And yeah,
we turned off his life support machine.
There was no way he
was going to survive it.
So it was very traumatic.
Six months of
thinking he's going to survive,
and then he isn't.
And he was the healthiest person,
honestly. He really was.
Yeah.
And then [laughs] your next employer
thinks, "Do you know what?
I've got a rabbit in the hat for you.
Don't you worry about it."
Yeah.
Fuck me.
[laughs]
Look, there's not one
part of me that thinks anyone's going to
hire you because of a sob story, but your
story is very interesting, and that
was something that
was itching in the back of
my brain,
so thank you very much for telling me
about that.
I'm going to work very closely with you to
help you get to the place that
you need to get to.
I've given you probably enough to get
started for now. I think
that the people watching this video
are going to be very
invested as well. So that's another
really good element of this. And
when this video goes out,
because it might go out
in a few days, maybe a week,
I want to make sure there
is a paper trail of posts
going out. And again,
the golden rule for that,
I don't care if it's not perfect
or it's not
the best edited, I just care
that it's done. Do we have a deal?
If you continue to do the work,
I'll continue to help you.
Thank you. We've got a deal.
And I will see you in September.
I've got you on WhatsApp now, and
I'll give you
my credit card,
and you can book yourself everything you
need.
[laughs] Wonderful. Thank you so much.
I'm excited.
All right.
Yeah.
Thank you very much for coming on this
call, and thank you for letting me record
it.
Thanks a lot. I'll see you soon.